Scooby-Doo meets the Yogi Bear!
Scooby-Doo! in Arabian Nights is a family, fantasy,
animation film directed by Jun Falkenstein.
Scooby-Doo and Shaggy travel to Arabia to become
the Caliph's Royal Food Tasters.
But they bite off more than they can chew and are forced to run for their lives!
It's a wild magic carpet ride as Scooby-Doo, Shaggy and their genie (Yogi Bear) and a jolly sailor named Sinbad (Magilla
Gorilla) take you on an adventure of mistaken identities, exotic locations and fun-filled action and surprises!
Scooby Doo / Boo-Boo Bear (voice), played by Don Messick.
Shaggy Rogers (voice), played by Casey Kasem.
Aliyah-Din (voice), played by Jennifer Hale.
Additional Voices (voice), played by Nick Jameson.
Additional Voices (voice), played by Tony Jay.
Yogi Bear / Royal Chef (voice), played by Greg Burson.
Scooby-Doo in Arabian Nights (also known as Arabian Nights) is a 1994 made-for-television film
produced by Hanna-Barbera Cartoons, and aired on syndication on September 3, 1994.
It is an adaptation of The Book of One Thousand and One Nights and features
appearances by Scooby-Doo and Shaggy Rogers, in wrap around segments.
The bulk of the special is devoted to two tales, one featuring Yogi Bear
and Boo-Boo Bear, and the other starring Magilla Gorilla.
It is animated with bright colors, stylized character designs and a more flat style compared to the previous television films, and
musically scored by veteran animation composer Steven Bernstein, showing strong influence from the high-budget Warner Bros.
Animation and Steven Spielberg cartoons of that era,
Tiny Toon Adventures and Animaniacs.
This would prove to be the last film in which Don Messick voices Scooby-Doo and Boo Boo before his retirement in 1996 (though he would voice Scooby-Doo one more
time in the Scooby-Doo Mystery video game), and the last in which Allan Melvin voices Magilla Gorilla (as well as his last film role overall).
The film explores themes of europe, europe journey, talking
dog, criminal investigation, woman director.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.